A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Projects, Series L FA348
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Alumni - Alumni Fund Campaigns - Correspondence, memos, etc., 1951 (Box 37, Folder 325)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Alumni - Alumni Fund Campaigns - Correspondence, memos, etc. & printed matter, 1952-1970 (Box 37, Folder 326)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Alumni - Alumni General Association, NAR President, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 327)
  NAR elected President of Association in 1954. Sole duty to preside at 1954 Alumni Commencement Luncheon.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Athletic Council, 1950-1959 (Box 37, Folder 328)
  Complimentary pass to athletic games. NAR sends champagne to hockey victory celebration.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - "Casque and Gauntlet", 1948-1968 (Box 37, Folder 329)
  Bulletins and invitations from NAR's Dartmouth Fraternity.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Charles Lathrop Pack Forestry Foundation, 1957-1961 (Box 37, Folder 330)
  Plans for logging Dartmouth forest lands in Northern New Hampshire.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Church of Christ at Dartmouth College, 1934-1970 (Box 37, Folder 331)
  Church where NAR taught Sunday School. Small NAR gifts to church. Some appeals declined. 1961 Building Fund gift.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Cirrotta, Raymond J., Matter, 1949-1950 (Box 37, Folder 332)
  Trustee handling of student death in a fight.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Class of 1930, 1950-1970 (Box 37, Folder 333)
  Bulletin of activities; NAR attendance at activities. NAR interest in Class activities.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Class of 1930 - Memorial Fund, 1947-1955 (Box 37, Folder 334)
  NAR contribution.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Class of 1930 - 25th Reunion, 1954-1955 (Box 37, Folder 335)
  NAR participation in reunion activities.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - College Club, 1937-1970 (Box 37, Folder 336)
  NAR buys bonds for building New York City Club House. Gives bond as donation. NAR paid dues but not an active member.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions, Miscellaneous, 1945-1971 (Box 38, Folder 337)
  Contributions for lectureship, memorial, Glee Club, renovation, Rugby Club, Hillel Program, 1930 Class Fund, Episcopal Student Association, Aquinas Fund, Tom Dent Cabin Fund, Outing Club, Development Council, E. M. Hopkins Fellowship Fund, General Fund; gift of Pan American Union Bulletin, gift is a piece of sculpture.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Orvil Dryfoos Professorship, 1963-1967 (Box 38, Folder 338)
  Release, correspondence, clippings, pledge 1963-1967.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Third Century Fund, 1967-1972 (Box 38, Folder 339)
  Appeal, memos, correspondence re contributions.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Figures, 1954-1967 (Box 38, Folder 340)
  Summary of NAR gifts, 1954-1967. Total as of 8/8/67 was $1,969,881.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Milburn McCarty Memorial Scholarship, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 341)
  Contribution - 1963; correspondence.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Skating Rink, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 342)
  Correspondence re rink and hockey team.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Alumni Funds, 1935-1971 (Box 38, Folder 343)
  Appeals; NAR contributions, 1935-1945, 1947-1958, 1960-1971.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Contributions - Alumni Funds, 1935-1971 (Box 38, Folder 344)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Degrees, Honorary, 1947-1959 (Box 38, Folder 345)
  Correspondence re recommendations for honorary degrees, faculty committee on degrees, suggestions from NAR.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Development Council, 1949-1957 (Box 39, Folder 346)
  NAR comment on fund raising activities of development council. Correspondents include NAR, Sydney Hayward.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Dickey, John S. - President, 1941-1970 (Box 39, Folder 347)
  Worked with NAR at Office of Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; clippings, personal correspondence re visits, meetings of Board of Trustees, trips; article by John S. Dickey; speeches by John S. Dickey; gifts given; correspondence re John S. Dickey's retirement.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Displaced Persons, 1948-1950 (Box 39, Folder 348)
  Correspondence re Displaced Persons as undergraduates at Dartmouth; correpondence with William Sudduth re individual student.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Dormitory (Proposed), 1949-1950 (Box 39, Folder 349)
  NAR offers to pay cost of plans for dormitory to be developed by Wallace Harrison. Dartmouth supplies information on size and facilities required. No follow-up. Correspondents include NAR, John S. Dickey.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Education Association, 1941-1970 (Box 39, Folder 350)
  NAR is a life member. Correspondence re reports, dues, NAR's membership, treasurer's reports.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Faculty, 1946-1952 (Box 39, Folder 351)
  1946 Committee report on faculty salaries. Student appeal for Spanish teacher not given tenure. (Appeal includes Rodman Clark Rockefeller's signature.) Correspondents include NAR, John S. Dickey.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Fraternities, 1948-1950 (Box 39, Folder 352)
  NAR and John S. Dickey discuss discrimination in fraternities. Dickey's plan to let undergraduates handle problem as long as progress is being made. Correspondents include NAR, John S. Dickey.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Friends of the Dartmouth Library, 1945-1954 (Box 39, Folder 353)
  NAR contributed in 1945 for funding of a Pan American Bulletin series. Later appeals declined.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course, 1947-1961 (Box 40, Folder 354)
  Text of lectures. Comments by Victor Borella. Reports on activities. Attack by "Chicago Tribune" on course at Dartmouth. NAR spoke on "Planning in a Democracy," 1948 and on "Point Four in a Chaotic World," 1951.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course, 1947-1961 (Box 40, Folder 355)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course, 1947-1961 (Box 40, Folder 356)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course - "Chicago Tribune" Articles, 1947-1956 (Box 40, Folder 357)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course - "Point Four in a Chaotic World", NAR Speaker, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 358)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Great Issues Course - Tenth Anniversary Convocation, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 359)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Center - General, 1947-1970 (Box 41, Folder 359.01)
  Search for proper memorial for E. M. Hopkins. Decision to build a Center. NAR personal tribute to Hopkins.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Center - Building Committee, NAR Chairman, 1955-1962 (Box 41, Folder 359.02)
  News clippings. Plans for Center. Interested participants. Controversy over architecture, costs, etc. Correspondents include Charles Kingsley, John Dickey, John Scotford, David Rockefeller.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Center - Building Committee, NAR Chairman, 1955-1962 (Box 41, Folder 0359.02A)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Center - Building Committee, NAR Chairman - General, 1955-1957 (Box 41, Folder 359.03)
  Meetings, memos, press releases. Minutes destroyed.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Center - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Pledge, 5/25/56, 1945-1958 (Box 41, Folder 359.04)
  NAR reaction, plans. John Davison Rockefeller Jr. letter.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Dinner, 2/5/58 - General, 1957-1958 (Box 41, Folder 359.05)
  NAR as Chairman of Dinner honoring Hopkins re his 80th birthday. Planning committees. Programs. Speeches.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Dinner, 2/5/58 - Dais, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 359.06)
  Seating arrangement.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - E. M. Hopkins Dinner, 2/5/58 - Invitation Letters, Appreciation Letters, Com. Lists, etc., 1958 (Box 41, Folder 359.07)
  Comments on dinner.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Investment Committee, 1950-1956 (Box 41, Folder 359.08)
  NAR comments on posible oil investment by college.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Invitations, Associations and Clubs, 1941-1968 (Box 42, Folder 359.09)
  Invitations to speak, to dine, to attend special functions of clubs, associations connected with Dartmouth. Many delcined.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Kemeny, John G. - President, 1970-1971 (Box 42, Folder 359.1)
  Correspondence re plan for co-education and year round operation.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Medical School, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 359.11)
  Printed material and memo re establishment and support for medical school.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Retirement and Insurance Program for College Employees, 1948-1950 (Box 42, Folder 359.12)
  Printed material; memos and correspondence re insurance and retirement benefits.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Robert C. Strong Memorial Fund, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 359.13)
  NAR contribution, 1947; booklet on Robert C. Strong and Memorial Fund.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1949-1954 (Box 42, Folder 359.14)
  Appeal; correspondence re John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Dartmouth for scholarships 1950 and other gifts.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Scholarships: Daniel Webster National Scholarships, NAR Pledge, 1952-1959 (Box 42, Folder 359.15)
  Correspondence re pledge for this scholarship by NAR, 1952. Transferral of payments on pledge; press release; revision of pledge, 1954; lists of recipients; completion of payments, 1959.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Scholarships: Daniel Webster National Scholarships - General, 1952-1956 (Box 42, Folder 359.16)
  Speeches on Daniel Webster. Correspondence re recipients and scholarships.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Trustees: Nelson A. Rockefeller, a Life Trustee, 1947-1954 (Box 42, Folder 359.17)
  Served as Alumni Trustee from 1942-1952; letter of nomination; correspondence re life members of Board of Trustees.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Trustees: Nelson A. Rockefeller, a Life Trustee - Minutes of Meetings, 1946-1952 (Box 42, Folder 359.18)
  Minutes of meetings, notices of memos on and correspondence relating to minutes.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Trustees: Nelson A. Rockefeller, a Life Trustee - Executive Committee, Meetings & Minutes, 1949-1950 (Box 42, Folder 359.19)
  Minutes.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Trustees: Nelson A. Rockefeller, a Life Trustee - Tuck School of Business Administration, 1950-1956 (Box 43, Folder 359.2)
  NAR on transfer committee to oversee Tuck School. Study of Harvard Business School system. Preparation of recommendations for school by committee. NAR meeting with students on social responsibilities.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Tucker Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 43, Folder 360)
  Appeals for contributions to religious work at Dartmouth declined.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Two Hundredth Anniversary Development Program - Steering Committee, Capital Gifts Campaign, 1957-1960 (Box 43, Folder 361)
  NAR served on Steering Committee. NAR contribution to campaign.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Wooden Indian, 1954-1955 (Box 43, Folder 362)
  NAR purchased wooden Indian to give to Dartmouth. Placed in Museum.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Zeta Chapter - Psi Upsilon, 1933-1972 (Box 43, Folder 363)
  NAR contribution to fraternity chapter house. Article on NAR in Fraternity magazine.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Zeta Chapter - Psi Upsilon - Gabaur, Peter Alden, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 364)
  Editor emeritus of "Diamond," fraternity magazine. Article on NAR. Requests for photographs.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material: ABC Report, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 365)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - The Protean Century, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 366)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Mass Media and Class Culture, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 367)
  Correspondents include F. Stanton.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Dartmouth Financial Report, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 368)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Class of 1930 Books, 1930-1970 (Box 44, Folder 369)
  Commencement, 10th, 25th, 40th Reunion.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Dartmouth Alumni, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 370)
  New York Area.
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Dartmouth Course Guide, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 371)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, 1962, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 372)
- Colleges - New Hampshire, Hanover, Dartmouth - Printed Material - Capital Gifts Campaign Final Report, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 373)
- Colleges - New Jersey - Rutgers, 1970-1971 (Box 45, Folder 374)
  NAR contributes $75,000 toward support of E. J. Hughes for a year as Professor at Eagleton Institute of Politics. Hughes gave a course on the presidency.
- Colleges - New Jersey - Princeton - General, 1949-1968 (Box 45, Folder 375)
  NAR contributions to parents committee, for dormitory, to $53,000,000 campaign.
- Colleges - New Jersey - Princeton - General, 1949-1968 (Box 45, Folder 0375A)
- Colleges - New Jersey - Princeton - James Forrestal Research Center, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 376)
  NAR contribution to Center.
- Colleges - New Jersey - Princeton - Woodrow Wilson School of Public & International Affairs, 1946-1956 (Box 45, Folder 377)
  NAR declines participation.
- Colleges - New Jersey - Princeton - Woodrow Wilson School of Public & International Affairs - NAR Contributions, 1955-1969 (Box 45, Folder 378)
  Parents Committee. Dormitory.
- Colleges - New York State, 1958-1971 (Box 45, Folder 379)
  Appeals declined. Some NAR contributions for special projects. Prior to 1958 destroyed.
- Colleges - New York State - Albany State University, Jane H. Todd Memorial Scholarship, 1967-1970 (Box 45, Folder 380)
  NAR contribution to Jane H. Todd Scholarship Fund.
- Colleges - New York State - State University of New York College in Westchester County - Purchase, 1967-1971 (Box 45, Folder 381)
  Protest against location of school, visits of classes to Pocantico Hills. Gift of collection of Greek items. Correspondents include Lipchitz, Neuberger.
- Colleges - New York State - Fredonia - State University College - Michael C. Rockefeller Arts Center, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 382)
  Dedication of Michael C. Rockefeller Art Center, Fredonia State University. NAR attended.
- Colleges - New York State - Fredonia - State University College - Michael C. Rockefeller Arts Center, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 0382A)
- Colleges - New York State - Ithaca, Cornell University, 1948-1971 (Box 45, Folder 383)
  NAR contributions 1965, 1967; some appeals declined.
- Colleges - New York State - Ithaca, Cornell University - Cornell Art Tours, 1965-1971 (Box 45, Folder 384)
  Sponsored by Cornell Women's Club. NAR contributions, 1968-1971.
- Colleges - New York State - Poughkeepsie, Vassar College, 1955-1971 (Box 45, Folder 385)
  NAR contribution 1961, 1959. Lent drawings 1960. Appeals declined. Previous to 1955 discarded.
- Colleges - New York State - Seneca Falls, Eisenhower College, 1966-1971 (Box 45, Folder 386)
  NAR contribution 1970, 1967. NAR at ground breaking 1966. Other appeals declined.
- Colleges - New York State - Syracuse, Syracuse University, 1949-1971 (Box 45, Folder 387)
  Appeals declined. NAR member of library associates 1970.
- Colleges - New York State - Tarrytown, Marymount College, 1962-1970 (Box 45, Folder 388)
  NAR contributions, 1962, 1969.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Miscellaneous, 1955-1970 (Box 46, Folder 389)
  Invitations and appeals declined. Previous to 1955 destroyed.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Brooklyn, Long Island University, 1954-1970 (Box 46, Folder 390)
  NAR contributions 1954-1964. Later appeals declined. Correspondence re contributions; clippings.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Pratt Institute, Pratt Graphic Arts Center, 1955-1968 (Box 46, Folder 391)
  NAR contributions, 1965, 1966.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Barnard College, 1951-1966 (Box 46, Folder 392)
  NAR donated a painting, 1966, other contributions in 1956, 1957. Other appeals declined.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University, 1950-1971 (Box 46, Folder 393)
  Some appeals declined. Previous to 1950 discarded.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - Contributions, 1950-1971 (Box 46, Folder 394)
  NAR given honorary LLD, 1967. Contributions 1961-1963, 1965, 1966. Clippings.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - Art Center, 1955-1962 (Box 46, Folder 395)
  Invitations declined.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - Maria Moors Cabot Award, 1956-1959 (Box 46, Folder 396)
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - Teachers' College, School of Nursing, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 397)
  Mrs. NAR contribution 1953.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - American Assembly, Graduate School of Business, 1956-1957 (Box 46, Folder 398)
  Correspondence re American Assembly meetins and reports.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Columbia University - School of Journalism, Francis A. Jamieson Memorial, 1965-1966 (Box 46, Folder 399)
  NAR contributions to Jamieson Memorial 1965 & 1966. Catalogue of the memorial collection given by Harry Frantz. Frantz sends NAR copies of some Francis A. Jamieson material, Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Fordham University, 1945-1969 (Box 46, Folder 400)
  NAR contributions, 1959; Fordham Law Alumni Association Luncheon. NAR spoke there, 1966.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Hunter College, 1949-1959 (Box 46, Folder 401)
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - General, 1950-1970 (Box 47, Folder 402)
  NAR an Albert Gallatin Associate; contribution, 1960; contribution to Martin Luther King Jr. Scholarship Fund, 1968; Financial report 1968-1969. Previous to 1950 discarded.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - Brazilian Institute, 1958-1967 (Box 47, Folder 403)
  NAR contributions, 1961-1963. Honorary Chairman. Appeals and invitations declined.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - Institute of Fine Arts - Conservation Center, 1966-1971 (Box 47, Folder 404)
  Tea House restoration. Contributions 1966, 1970, 1971.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - NYU Hall of Fame Committee, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 405)
  Correspondence re William Gorgas.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - Inter-American Law Institute, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 406)
  Correspondence with Arthur Vanderbilt
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - New York University - NYU Law Center, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 407)
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Yeshiva University - Medical Center - Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 1955-1961 (Box 47, Folder 408)
  NAR contribution 1953, 1958. Appeals and invitations to serve declined. NAR honorary degree recipient, 1958.
  See also Degrees, Honorary - Yeshiva folder.
- Colleges - New York State - New York City, Brooklyn, Bronx - Yeshiva University - Medical Center - Contributions - Plaques, etc., 1955-1961 (Box 47, Folder 409)
  NAR contribution 1958. Appeals and invitations declined. Previous to 1955 discarded.
- Colleges - North Carolina, 1952-1971 (Box 47, Folder 410)
- Colleges - Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, 1951-1971 (Box 47, Folder 411)
  Appeals declined. 1966 contribution to John Carroll University, Cleveland.
- Colleges - Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon - Defiance College, 1962-1967 (Box 47, Folder 412)
  NAR contribution 1962.
- Colleges - Pennsylvania, 1952-1971 (Box 47, Folder 413)
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - Philadelphia, Temple University & Survey of Federal Reorganization, 1952-1954 (Box 48, Folder 414)
  NAR contribution to cost of Temple University studies of government organization. Prepared for Special Committee on Government Organization of which NAR was chair.
  See also: RG 4, Washington, D.C. Series.
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - University of Pennsylvania - General, 1948-1971 (Box 48, Folder 415)
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - University of Pennsylvania - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1956-1965 (Box 48, Folder 416)
  Correspondence re the Institute with Robert Strauss-Hupe; contribution 1965. Printed maerial discarded.
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - University of Pennsylvania - Kenneth E. Appel Professorship of Psychiatry, 1966-1971 (Box 48, Folder 417)
  NAR contribution, 1966.
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - University Park, Penn State University, 1954-1964 (Box 48, Folder 418)
  Appeals declined; correspondence with Dr. Milton Eisenhower re Brazilian Room. 1954 contribution for Eisenhower Chapel.
- Colleges - Pennsylvania - University Park, Penn State University - Contributions, 1955-1957 (Box 48, Folder 419)
- Colleges - South Carolina, 1947-1970 (Box 48, Folder 420)
  Appeals declined or referred to Rockefeller Foundation.
- Colleges - Tennessee - Miscellaneous, 1950-1968 (Box 48, Folder 421)
- Colleges - Tennessee - Morristown, Morristown Junior College, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 422)
  NAR contribution, 1954.
- Colleges - Tennessee - Nashville, Fisk University, 1947-1963 (Box 48, Folder 423)
  Correspondence; appeals referred to Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include John Davison Rockefeller, 3rd.
- Colleges - Tennessee - Scarritt College for Christian Workers, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 424)
- Colleges - Tennessee - Vanderbilt University, Cordell Hull Foundation for International Education, 1946-1952 (Box 48, Folder 425)
- Colleges - Texas, 1949-1969 (Box 48, Folder 426)
  NAR contribution to Rice University, 1949. Correspondence with Winthrop Rockefeller. All other appeals declined.
- Colleges - Texas - Austin, University of Texas, 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 427)
  Appeals declined. Note from Winthrop Rockefeller.
- Colleges - Utah, 1969 (Box 48, Folder 428)
- Colleges - Vermont, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 429)
  Appeals for Goddard College by Chester Bowles.
- Colleges - Vermont - Bennington, Bennington College, 1963-1967 (Box 48, Folder 430)
  NAR contributions 1967, 1966, 1963. Oscar Ruebhausen, Chairman of the Board.